RESUME

Ibrahim Zerlin Bezara

Birthdate: February 28th, 1981. **Address:** 6807 Hall of Fame Blvd

Midland, TX 79706

USA

Mobile: 1-575-631-5789

Email: ibrahimzerlin@hotmail.com



Place of Birth: Maturin / Monagas State. Venezuela Citizenship: US citizen & Venezuelan Citizenship

Marital status: Married

Profile: I am an Electronic Engineer, proactive, willing to accept any kind of challenges. I have a very high sense of commitment. I have 18 years of wireline oil field service experience. I am used to manage groups of 100+ people and overseeing 10M-50M annual budget. I am looking for a position that can offer me growth opportunities inside or outside my field of work. I am willing to relocate nationally or internationally.

EDUCATION

- 2002 Bachelor Science Electronic Engineering. Universidad Rafael Belloso Chacin Maracaibo, Venezuela
- 2003 Halliburton Open Hole & Cased Hole Field Engineering School. Fort Worth, USA

KEY COMPETENCIES

- 18 years of experience in logging and perforating services Open Hole and Cased Hole Services.
- 11 months in automation and control equipments.

Languages: Spanish (mother tongue)

English (Proficient: Speak; Read and Write)

WORK HISTORY

APR 2020- PRESENT UNIVERSAL PRESSURE PUMPING LLC US Cementing Manager

- Managing day to day cement operations with 55 direct report employees.
- Responsible for US Cementing PNL Statement.
- Responsible for managing internal and external customer expectations and increasing revenue and profitability for the assigned area.
- Directly responsible to identify, lead, manage, and develop District Manager(s) to Company standards and to ensure the same level of development is cascaded throughout the organization.
- Ensure District Manager(s) build and develop positive relationships with internal and external customers.
- Provide leadership and management to foster a safe and effective working atmosphere.
- Collaborate with cross functional teams and staff from all levels of the organization to deliver results.
- Promote a diverse and inclusive work environment where employees of all backgrounds feel included and their contributions are valued.
- Effectively manage CAPEX and OPEX and develop an organizational culture that is accountable for fiscal responsibility in all areas.

Aug 2019- Apr 2020 UNIVERSAL WIRELINE LLC Operations Director - West Texas

Responsibilities included:

Plans and directs all aspects of the policies, practices, and procedures that affect wireline operations and the wireline sales process. Key focus areas include safety, quality, performance, profitability, compliance, equipment, people management and process improvement to achieve sustainable growth.

- Designs, develops, supports, implements and drives strategies to maximize performance and achieve company objectives.
- Utilize business acumen to align strategy, goals and objectives to the overall mission and vision of the organization.
- Responsible for managing internal and external customer expectations and increasing revenue and profitability for the assigned area.
- Directly responsible to identify, lead, manage, and develop District Manager(s) to Company standards and to ensure the same level of development is cascaded throughout the organization.
- Ensure District Manager(s) build and develop positive relationships with internal and external customers.
- Promptly address and resolve concerns and disputes among team members and customers with the goal of building a stronger, more cohesive work group.
- Provide leadership and management to foster a safe and effective working atmosphere.
- Collaborate with cross functional teams and staff from all levels of the organization to deliver results.
- Promote a diverse and inclusive work environment where employees of all backgrounds feel included and their contributions are valued.
- Make employment decisions in a manner consistent with all Company policies, including the Company's Equal Employment Opportunity and Anti-Harassment Policy.

- Communicate and ensure that District Manager(s) understand and comply with all policies and procedures.
- Provide strategic oversight and management of equipment and asset integrity within the assigned area to include product lifecycle management, maintenance, inventory, critical spares and security.
- Accountable for all relevant Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) for Universal Wireline and other metrics such as EBITA, TRIR, NPT, Repair and Maintenance costs, and employee related metrics.
- Perform wellsite audits and follow-up reviews to ensure a safe work environment, proper maintenance of equipment and machinery, and effective employee engagement.
- Oversee incident investigations and ensure appropriate corrective actions are completed and implemented based upon findings.
- Collaborate with Supply Chain to develop appropriate sourcing, procurement and logistics strategies to ensure delivery of supplies, equipment, materials and services for the wireline business
- Effectively manage CAPEX and OPEX and develop an organizational culture that is accountable for fiscal responsibility in all areas.
- Responsible for validating that accounting has accurate and timely information for billing and payables.
- Maintain and demonstrate integrity and accountability in reporting and all facets of the business.
- Make sound and timely decisions to maximize performance, promote a safe work environment and attain operational excellence.

JAN 2019- JUN 2019 ALLIED HORIZONTAL WIRELINE SERVICES District Operations Manager - North East

JUN 2018– JAN 2019 ALLIED HORIZONTAL WIRELINE SERVICES District Manager – West Texas

MAR 2018– JUN 2018
ALLIED HORIZONTAL WIRELINE SERVICES
District Operations Manager – West Texas

JUL2016- MAR 2018
ALLIED HORIZONTAL WIRELINE SERVICES
Service Quality Manager - West Texas

APR 2016 – JUL2016 C & J ENERGY SERVICES (CASED HOLE SOLUTIONS) Senior Completion Engineer

OCT 2002 – SEP2015 HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES Multiple Positions and Responsibilities

JAN2015 – SEP2015 HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES TITLE: DISTRICT PSL SERVICE MANAGER, WPS

Aug2013 – Jan2015 HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES TITLE: FIELD SERVICE MANAGER, WPS

JAN2013 – AUG2013 HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES

TITLE: PERFORMANCE DEVELOPMENT COORDINATOR, WPS

JAN2012 – JAN2013 HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES TITLE: CASED HOLE SERVICE COORDINATOR, WPS

AUG2011 – JAN2012

HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES

TITLE: OPEN HOLE SERVICE COORDINATOR, WPS

OCT2008 - AUG2011

HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES
TITLE: GENERAL FIELD PROFESSIONAL, WPS

Nov 2006 - Oct 2008

HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES (HALLIBURTON ARGENTINA S.A)

TITLE: FIELD PROFESSIONAL SR, WPS

JUL 2006 - OCT 2006

HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES (HALLIBURTON LATIN AMERICA)

TITLE: FIELD PROFESSIONAL, WPS

APR 2002 - JUL2006

HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES (HALLIBURTON DE VENEZUELA S.A)

TITLE: FIELD PROFESSIONAL, WPS

OCT 2001 - APR2002

HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES (HALLIBURTON DE VENEZUELA S.A)

TITLE: ASSOCIATE FIELD PROFESSIONAL, WPS

Wireline related Responsibilities and qualifications included:

- Interact daily with the Field Service Manager and District Manager regarding the progress of field engineer and operator training.
- Accompany crews to all operations which require specific training due to crew inexperience
- Coach field engineers and operators to facilitate efficient and effective development of the skills associated with those positions
- Introduce the career progression process to the field employees, and assist the operations management team in the evaluation of the same field employees as part of the promotion process.
- Ensure that all processes and procedures are implemented and being used effectively in the district.
- Perform root cause analysis and closure of all SQ issues suffered in the district, including reporting to the client and sharing with other districts.
- Work with field crews to minimize lost time during ongoing operational issues at the wellsite by assisting in troubleshooting.
- Extensive knowledge in Cased Hole pumpdown plug/perf Operations.
- Manage and Coordinate Hobbs District 100+ employees wireline operation.
- Responsible for Profit and Lost, employee management and career development, inventory management, sales, engineering, maintenance, operations, service, HSE, quality, training.
- Worked closely with sales on pricing planning based on operation cost and margin predictions to establish a market strategy.
- Contact and meet with Customers to support operations.
- Worked together with other product service line managers to develop new business opportunities.
- Headcount and career development plan for operators and field engineers.

- Oversee pre and post job execution to ensure all crews are following the standard operational procedures.
- Supervise to ensure operations stays on compliance with regulations for radioactive source in oilfield operations associated with formation evaluation.
- Supervise to ensure operations stay on compliance with regulations for Explosive ATF regulations associated with Cased Hole Perforating and other services.
- Field Audits to guarantee operations and job executions are in compliance with standards.
- Conduct failure and incidents Root Cause Analysis and action plans to improve efficiency and operation's safety record.
- Conduct Daily PSL safety meetings and Weekly PSL management team meetings. Manage and Coordinate human resources and assets to deliver service quality on locations and ensure customer satisfaction.
- Check, Calibrate and run open hole services: HRIT/ DLLT/ SDLT/ DSNT/ SFTIV/ SFTT/ SED/ CNSG/ CASTV/ EMIT/ XRMI/ WSTT/ XACT/ FWST/ SDDT/ MSFL/ FIAC/ FACT/NGRT/ EJAR/ ICT/ IDT/ RWCH/ HRAI/ H4TG/ HDIL/ HDSN/ HECT/ HETS/ HFWS/ HNGR/ HSDL/ GTET/ BCAS/ SDLT-I/ DSN-I/ HRAI/ CNSG-I/ DLLT-I/WST-I/ACRt, MRIL.
- Check, calibrate and run cased hole services: CASTV/ CBL/ PLT/ GPWP/ GPLT/ HGNC/ RCBL/ CBT/ RMT-E, gravity dump bailer, plugs and packers setting, stim tube stimulation and perforating services.
- Basic knowledge of check, calibrate and run tool pusher logging, freepoint, backoff, chemical cutter.
- Experience Working at offshore; land and inland water locations.
- Experience Using Halliburton Warrior System, Excell 2000 A, B, C, F, G. Logic IQ A&B
- Extensive knowledge of Open Hole and Cased Hole wireline and tool fishing operations.
- Extensive knowledge of Cased Hole wireline greaseless operations.

Major Career Achievements:

- 2020 Open a new wireline company from ground up. Including buying equipment, building facility and hiring all personnel.
- 2018 Full Greaseless implementation in Allied Horizontal Wireline. Equipment and Procedures.
- 2015 Deliver Financial Performance workshop participation.
- 2012 Halliburton Wireline PSL Excellence Workshop participation.
- 2011 Creator of the Open Hole Insite tools / Cased Hole tools Logging combination. (One logging pass). Received a Halliburton MVP for it.
- 2011 Halliburton Distinctive Service Quality employee of the Year for Wireline PSL
- 2003 Top grade in Halliburton 3 month logging school (Score 100).
- 2003 Participate and work for 4 months in Halliburton Sinopec Project. Houston, TX (New generation of Open Hole tools)

Locations that I have worked on:

- 2003 and 2008-2015 USA (Houston, Hobbs, Odessa and Liberal)
- 2006-2008 Argentina (Neuquén, Lujan del Cuyo, Comodoro Rivadavia).
- 2006 Colombia (Neiva and Pto Boyoca).
- 2004 Mexico (Revnosa and Veracruz).
- 2002-2006 Venezuela (Maturín, Las Morochas and Barinas).

- 2016-2018 C&J (Hobbs, San Antonio, TX) AHWS (Midland, TX Victoria, TX)
- 2019 Irwin (AHWS).

SEPT 2000 – Aug 2001 PDVSA – EXPLORATION & PRODUCTION AUTOMATION ENGINEER.

Responsibilities included:

· Maintenance of remote control and automation system (S.C.A.D.A) in Motatan I, II, III and Barua V.

FEB 2000 – SEPT 2000 PDVSA – EXPLORATION & PRODUCTION INTERNSHIP AND THESIS DEVELOPMENT.

THESIS TITLE: DESING AND IMPLEMENTATION OF REMOTE CONTROL AND AUTOMATION SYSTEM (S.C.A.D.A) IN MOTATAN I, II, II AND BARUA V FLOW STATIONS. TRUJILLO STATE/VENEZUELA.

Responsibilities included:

· Development and Compilation of RTU's (Remote Terminal Unit) programs in Motatan I, II, III and Barua

V flow stations.

· Check and replacement of different equipments: electrical valves, flow meters, Pressure meter.

PERSONAL REFERENCES

Mark Montgomery, Allied Horizontal Corporate Manager 1-412-807-1691

Mark.Montgomery@ahwireline.com

Lee Galan, Reliable Wireline Sales Manager 1-325-315-1584 Leegalan14@yahoo.com